Davis Family Diaries WLU.Coll.0293
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Davis Family Diaries
Inclusive 1917-1959
Bulk 1917-1933
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Davis, William Couch
Davis, Mary Anderson
WLU.Coll.0293
1 Linear Feet
Biographical / Historical
William Davis was a 1909 graduate of Washington and Lee University. He previously graduated from West Point, Virginia high school in 1904.
Scope and Contents
This a a collection of diaries of William Couch Davis, Jr., and his wife, Mary Anderson Davis, including accounts of William's jobs in France (1917-19), Cuba, Savannah, and Norfolk. They include many details about the Davis family of West Point, Virginia. One of Mary's diaries covers their first married year (1924-25) in Cuba and others cover their trips (1935-1959) out west in Canada and to Central America and Europe.
Separated Materials
The control folder for the WLU COll. # 0293, Davis Family Diaries, and the William Couch Davis, Jr. oversize documents including certificates and diplomas have been removed to OVERSIZE Drawer 27.
Diaries; Georgia -- Savannah; Virginia -- Norfolk; Central America; Canada; Europe; France; Voyages and travels; Cuba; Virginia -- West Point; Davis family
- Honorable Discharge Paper for W.C. Davis, Jr., 1918; 1 Item (Folder 1, Oversize data_value_missing_80f04de556e642a3c36775f65502f755)
  Davis, William Couch
- Document of Davis's Appointment to Corporal of 318th Infantry, 1917; United States. Army; United States. Army. Infantry; 1 Item (Folder 1, Oversize data_value_missing_80156854b385df82dbbe9cb1f914eb5e)
  Infantry; Davis, William Couch
- Document of Davis's Appointment to 2nd Lieutenant of Engineers in National Army, 1918; 1 Item (Folder 1, Oversize data_value_missing_c834082524660557d0fd8bc1ca5658f1)
- West Point Public School Diploma, 1914; 1 Item (Folder 1, Oversize data_value_missing_3d7ed6f0f37d67d10167ac1553520abb)
  Virginia -- West Point; Davis, William Couch
- William Davis's Diaries, 1919-1926; Davis, William Couch; 5 Item (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  The 1919 diary has notes from 1920 and 1921. The 1922 diary is mostly written from Nashville, Tn. The 1924 is written in Cuba when Davis was on his honeymoon. The 1925 and 1926 are written in Virginia and Florida.
  Tennessee -- Nashville; France -- Paris; Cuba; Virginia -- West Point; Florida
- William Davis's Diaries, 1927-1928; Davis, William Couch; 2 Item (Box 1)
  The 1927 diary was written in Florida and Savannah. The 1928 was written in Savannah.
  Florida -- Miami; Georgia -- Savannah
- William Davis's Diaries, 1929-1932; Davis, William Couch; 3 Item (Box 1)
  Diaries; South Carolina -- Sumter
- William Davis's Diaries, 1933-1935; Davis, William Couch; 3 Item (Box 1)
  Florida
- William Davis's Diaries, 1939-1940; Davis, William Couch; 2 Item (Box 2)
  Virginia -- Richmond; Virginia -- Hopewell; Virginia -- West Point
- Mary Davis's Diaries, 1925-1929; Davis, Mary Anderson; 5 Item (Box 2)
  Mary started writing her first diary in 1925 on her honeymoon in Cuba after she got married to William.
  Georgia -- Savannah; Virginia -- West Point; Florida; Cuba
- Mary Davis's Trip Diaries, 1935-1959; Davis, Mary Anderson; 8 Item (Box 2)
  1935 - Mexico1939 - Canada (canoeing and fishing trip)1940 - Gila National Forest, New Mexico1949 - Yucatan1951 - Guatemala1959 - 2 diaries of European trip
  France -- Paris; Virginia -- Norfolk; Guatemala; Mexico -- Yucatán (State); Canada; Mexico; Europe; New Mexico -- Gila National Forest